<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Eclipse Soundscapes</string>
    <string name="app_name_version">%1$s v%2$s</string>
    <string name="eclipse_features">Features</string>
    <string name="eclipse_center">Center</string>
    <string name="eclipse_center_title">Eclipse Center</string>

    <!-- General -->
    <string name="media">Media</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>

    <string name="north">North</string>
    <string name="south">South</string>
    <string name="east">East</string>
    <string name="west">West</string>

    <string name="date">Date</string>
    <string name="time">Time</string>
    <string name="type">Type</string>
    <string name="features">Features</string>

    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="open_settings">Open Settings</string>
    <string name="open_description">Open Description of \n%1$s</string>
    <string name="description">Description</string>
    <string name="instructions">Instructions</string>
    <string name="welcome">Welcome</string>
    <string name="language">Language</string>
    <string name="permissions">Permissions</string>

    <string name="continue_text">Continue</string>
    <string name="skip">Skip</string>
    <string name="close">Close</string>
    <string name="play">Play</string>
    <string name="pause">Pause</string>
    <string name="back">Back</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>

    <string name="years">Years</string>
    <string name="months">Months</string>
    <string name="hours">Hours</string>
    <string name="days">Days</string>
    <string name="minutes">Minutes</string>
    <string name="seconds">Seconds</string>
    <string name="min_abbr">Min</string>
    <string name="sec_abbr">Sec</string>

    <string name="show_next">Show next</string>
    <string name="show_prev">show previous</string>

    <!-- permissions -->
    <string name="location_permission">Location permission</string>
    <string name="error_finding_location">Unable to determine your current location</string>
    <string name="permission_denied">Permission denied</string>
    <string name="location_disabled_message">Location disabled.\nTo continue, enable location services from your device settings.</string>
    <string name="enable_location">Enable Location</string>

    <string name="device_settings_permission">To continue, please allow access to your location from your device settings.</string>
    <string name="app_settings_permission">To continue, please allow access to your location from the application settings.</string>

    <!-- Notifications -->
    <string name="notification_channel_desc">Display notifications about an upcoming eclipse.</string>
    <string name="default_eclipse_reminder">The Solar Eclipse is going to begin soon.</string>
    <string name="total_eclipse_reminder">The Total Solar Eclipse is going to begin soon.</string>
    <string name="annular_eclipse_reminder">The Annular Solar Eclipse is going to begin soon.</string>

    <string name="notification_first_contact">The Solar Eclipse has begun!</string>
    <string name="notification_totality">The Total Solar Eclipse has begun!</string>
    <string name="notification_annular_start">The Annular Solar Eclipse has begun!</string>
    <string name="notification_annular_phase_start">The Annular Phase has begun!</string>
    <string name="notification_annularity">Annularity has begun!</string>
    <string name="tap_listen">Tap to listen now.</string>

    <!-- Settings -->
    <string name="license">License</string>
    <string name="enable_notifications">Enable Notifications</string>
    <string name="access_location">Access Location</string>
    <string name="open_src_libs">Open Source Libraries</string>
    <string name="photo_credits">Photo Credits</string>
    <string name="privacy_policy">Privacy Policy</string>
    <string name="tos">Terms of Service</string>
    <string name="legal">Legal</string>
    <string name="libs_in_use">Libraries We Use</string>
    <string name="jsyn_lib">JSyn</string>

    <string name="menu">Menu</string>
    <string name="about_us_details">The Eclipse Soundscapes mobile application is a product of the Eclipse Soundscapes Project, which is an enterprise ARISA Lab, LLC.
        The Eclipse Soundscapes Project aims to engage ALL learners with astrophysics, with an intentional focus on inclusion and accessibility. For more information, visit EclipseSoundscapes.org.
        The development of the Eclipse Soundscapes mobile application is funded by NASA Space Science Education Consortium.</string>

    <!-- Eclipse Center -->
    <string name="eclipse_center_lockout_details">Updated Eclipse data coming soon.</string>
    <string name="eclipse_countdown_title">Countdown Until Next Eclipse</string>
    <string name="next_eclipse_info">Next Eclipse Info</string>
    <string name="next_eclipse_user_location">Next Eclipse at Your Location</string>
    <string name="next_eclipse_simulated_location">Next Eclipse at Closest Location</string>
    <string name="countdown_format">Countdown until eclipse from your location, %1$s years, %2$s months, %3$s days, %4$s hours, %5$s minutes and %6$s seconds</string>
    <string name="event_section_desc">Events at closest location are below. Events include your local time and universal time.</string>
    <string name="event_desc_format">Event from closest location, %1$s, local time, %2$s, universal time, %3$s</string>
    <string name="eclipse_center_permission">You don\'t want to miss this amazing astronomical event! We\'ll need your location to access this feature.\nPress anywhere on the screen to continue.</string>

    <string name="location_search">Finding your location…</string>

    <string name="outside_eclipse_path">Unfortunately the Eclipse is not visible from your location</string>
    <string name="get_closest_location">Get closest location to Eclipse</string>

    <string name="eclipse_center_title_format">%1$s:</string>
    <string name="eclipse_type">Eclipse Type</string>
    <string name="location_latitude">Location\'s Latitude</string>
    <string name="location_longitude">Location\'s Longitude</string>
    <string name="lat_lng_format">%1$.3f&#xb0; %2$s</string>
    <string name="percent_eclipse">% Eclipse</string>
    <string name="totality_duration">Duration of Totality</string>
    <string name="annular_duration">Duration of Annularity</string>
    <string name="eclipse_duration">Duration of Eclipse</string>
    <string name="eclipse_event">Event</string>
    <string name="local_time">(Local Time)</string>
    <string name="universal_time">Universal Time</string>
    <string name="time_ut">(UT)</string>

    <string name="eclipse_type_full">Total Solar Eclipse</string>
    <string name="eclipse_type_partial">Partial Solar Eclipse</string>
    <string name="eclipse_type_none">No Solar Eclipse</string>
    <string name="eclipse_type_annular">Annular Solar Eclipse</string>
    <string name="eclipse_type_unkown">Unknown</string>

    <string name="eclipse_start_partial">Start of Partial Eclipse</string>
    <string name="eclipse_start_full">Start of Total Eclipse</string>
    <string name="eclipse_end_partial">End of Partial Eclipse</string>
    <string name="eclipse_end_full">End of Total Eclipse</string>
    <string name="eclipse_max">Maximum Eclipse</string>

    <string name="active_event">Tap to hear about what\'s currently happening!</string>

    <string name="next_live_event_countdown">Next live event in \n%1$s</string>

    <!-- Eclipse Features -->
    <string name="first_contact_description">This is the first moment that the moon, slowly moving from left to right, appears to touch the sun.
        The intensity of the sun\'s light makes it unsafe to look at without special eye protection until the totality, the few minutes during which the moon completely eclipses the sun.
        The two celestial bodies appear to be the same size, although the sun\'s light is so bright that it obliterates all of the moon\'s features causing the moon to appear as a smooth, obsidian disk.
        For the next several minutes, the moon\'s black disk will creep across the sun, progressively blocking more of sun\'s light and heat until the totality.
        \n\nYou can use this time to explore Rumble Map images and audio descriptions of phenomena unique to a total eclipse.
        In the moments before, during and after totality, this app will provide a play-by-play of the action, providing images and descriptions of this rare and fascinating stellar event.
        \n\nAdditional scientific info:\nThe outer atmosphere of the Sun, called the corona, is usually not visible from the surface of the Earth.
        To study the corona, scientists send satellites into space to make observations of the corona in wavelengths of light that the human eye cannot see, such as this image of the Sun in X-rays taken by the X-ray Telescope on the Hinode spacecraft.
        This X-ray image shows the view of the Sun being eclipsed by the moon a seen from space. A total solar eclipse provides a rare opportunity to see the corona from Earth in visible light.</string>

    <string name="bailys_beads_description">On the right side of the moon, orbs of glowing sunlight shimmer off the edge of the moon\'s black disk.
        Called Baily\'s Beads, these final areas of the sun\'s light appear as glimmering pearls on a wire, made intensely bright by the absence of light surrounding them.
        \n\nExplanation of what you might feel as you interact: \nOn the Rumble Map, explore the features between the moon, the sun\'s corona and Baily\'s beads which are intense and irregular.
        \n\nAdditional scientific info: \nEven this small section of the Sun\'s light cannot be viewed without special eye protection.
        Please use special eclipse glasses or filters if viewing this feature directly on the Sun with your eyes.
        \nBaily\'s beads are caused because the moon\'s surface is not a smooth, perfect sphere.
        Rays of light peer through the ravines and valleys between mountains on the moon causing this spectacular feature.</string>

    <string name="corona_description">During the totality, the moon completely covers the sun\'s glowing orb, and the sun\'s outer atmosphere is revealed.
        As if the moon were the center of a celestial sunflower, the corona appears as soft white petals, massive flumes of faint light that taper out across the sky.
        Closer to the surface of the moon\'s flat ebony circle, the corona is a swirling chaos of loops and flares. Intense fiery lines of light appear to ignite the moon\’s black edge.
        \n\nHow to interact with the Rumble Map:\nOn the Rumble Map, explore the features between the moon and the sun\’s corona.
        You will hear/feel variations as your fingers pass over different features of the corona.
        \n\nAdditional scientific info:\nThe corona is the thin outer atmosphere of the Sun.
        With temperatures at over 1 million degrees Fahrenheit, it radiates light in wavelengths that are too short for the human eye to see (like X-rays) and that are absorbed by the Earth\'s atmosphere.
        However, the corona reflects some of the white light from the Sun\'s photosphere below it. This faint reflection is only seen when the much brighter photosphere is blocked, like during a total eclipse.</string>

    <string name="diamond_ring_description">On the left side of the black moon, a sliver of sunlight blasts into view with white-hot intensity.
        As the area of re-emerging sunlight grows, it resembles a diamond, beaming out its brilliant light from its setting on the circular ring of the moon\'s edge.
        \n\nAdditional scientific info:\nEven this small section of the Sun\'s light cannot be viewed without special eye protection.
        Please use special eclipse glasses or filters if viewing this feature directly on the Sun with your eyes.
        \nAs the moon barely moves away from the solar surface, the powerful light of the Sun peers around the side of the moon.
        The Sun\'s light is so intense that even this small fraction of it dominates the sky.</string>

    <string name="helmet_streamers_description">Projections of light from the sun\'s outer atmosphere called helmet streamers extend in all directions from behind the moon.
        In contrast to the black, featureless moon, the pale, wispy streamers appear as delicate as lace. The largest streamers have a tapered shape that resemble flower petals.
        They extend from opposite sides of the sun, with smaller rays of light between them.
        \n\nExplanation of what you might feel as you interact:\nAs you trace your finger along a helmet streamer, you can feel the smooth arches come to long sharp points as they extend from the base of the Sun outward.
        \n\nAdditional scientific info:\nHelmet streamers get their shape from two different processes.
        A streamer\'s arch shape is the result of magnetic fields from the Sun reaching out into the corona and then arching back down to the surface of the sun to connect to regions of opposite magnetic polarity.
        The long, pointed tops of helmet streamers come from streams of gas flowing out from the corona into interplanetary space forming the solar wind.</string>

    <string name="prominence_description">Fiery loops of hot pink light appear to leap off the moon\'s black surface.
        With the sheer white corona as their backdrop, these pink prominences seem to dance above the moon like lines of liquid neon.
        \n\nExplanation of what you might feel as you interact:\nYou will notice a sharp contrast when you interact with a prominence due to its intense brightness relative to both the moon and the sun’s corona.
        \n\nAdditional scientific info:\nProminences are magnetic fields that are filled with very dense material making them much brighter than the surrounding background.
        The magnetic fields of prominences can be very complicated giving them complex and dynamic shapes.</string>

    <string name="totality_description">This is the full eclipse, when the moon\'s black disk completely covers the sun.
        Now, in the absence of the sun\'s full light, its massive outer corona is revealed. Uniquely visible during a full eclipse, grand flourishes of light called helmet streamers extend in all directions behind the moon\’s black disk.
        At the edge of the moon, the helmet streamers are intensely bright, fading to wisps of ghostly white as they stretch across space, far from the moon, like flower petals.
        \n\nExplanation of what you might feel as you interact:\nOn the Rumble Map, explore the difference between the moon and the sun\'s corona.
        \n\nAdditional scientific info:\nYou may notice changes in temperature and natural sounds, such a birds and wind during the total eclipse.
        \nDuring the total solar eclipse, and only during totality, you can view the corona of the Sun without eye protection.
        The Sun\'s outer atmosphere, the corona, is in full display and viewable from the ground. The highly structured nature of the corona is clearly evident.
        This structure is caused by the Sun\'s intense and complicated magnetic fields interacting with the material that makes up the corona.
        This material is called a plasma, which is like a gas, but is susceptible to magnetic fields.
        The magnetic fields can then shape the plasma in the corona into the complicated patterns that are viewable during the eclipse.</string>

    <string name="sun_as_star_description">Framed by a larger view of space, the solar wind draws the helmet streamers far out into space as other stars come into view.
        Many of these stars also have planets orbiting them. Those planets can eclipse their parent star just as the moon eclipsed our Sun.
        Scientists can detect planets eclipsing their stars and determine both how far the planet is from its star and the planet’s mass.
        From these clues and other observations, scientists are attempting to discover if there is life on these other planets that may be experiencing their own eclipse.</string>

    <string name="annular_start_description">During an annular eclipse, the Moon blocks the Sun, but not completely. From Earth, the Moon does not appear big enough to block out the Sun entirely.
        \n\nThis image is from moments after what is called “First Contact.” At First Contact the  Sun appears as a glowing, white disk against a black background. On the left side of the Sun, a small, U-shaped area appears missing from the Sun\’s perfect circle shape.
        This missing area is the Moon as it creeps in front of the Sun slowly starting to block out the Sun\’s light. The Moon appears to be taking a bite out of the Sun like a bite out of a cookie.
        \n\nUsually the Moon\’s deep craters make the Moon appear rough. But now, the Sun\’s light is so bright that it erases all of the Moon\’s features. This causes the Moon to appear black and smooth like glass. The intensity of the Sun\’s light makes it unsafe to look at the annular eclipse without always wearing special eye protection.
        \n\nThis image was taken in 2012 by astronomer and science writer Dr. Rick Fienberg. Dr. Fienberg used a digital camera and zoom lens capped with a special-purpose filter to block 99.999% of the Sun\’s dangerously bright light. You should never  take photos of an eclipse without a special solar filter.
        The bright light of an eclipse can damage a camera, as well as your eyes! A solar filter helps protect the camera and your eyes. A solar filter fits over the front of a telescope lens and is specifically designed to limit the amount of light without adding color.
        \n\nDr. Fienberg has been chasing total solar eclipses around the world for 30 years! He observed and photographed this eclipse from a cruise ship in the Pacific Ocean near Australia.
        \n\nVisit the Rumble Map to explore this image through touch and sound. The absence of light is silent and still. Can you feel and hear where the Moon\’s dark rounded edge begins to block out the bright edge of the Sun?</string>

    <string name="annular_phase_start_description">This image is of the phenomenon called “Baily\’s Beads.” In this stage the Moon has moved in front of the Sun. The Sun\’s light is reduced to a thin C-shape or crescent, shining at the edge of the Moon.
        \n\nBaily’s Beads look like a few glowing pearls at the ends of the crescent. Baily\’s Beads occur because the Moon\’s surface is not smooth. It is covered by mountains and valleys. Baily\’s Beads are caused by Sunlight beaming between the mountains and through the valleys on the Moon when the Sun begins to peek around the Moon\’s edge.
        \n\nAfter Baily’s Beads disappear, the Annular Phase begins.
        \n\nBaily\'s Beads are named for an English astronomer named Sir Francis Baily. Sir Francis published his observations after seeing these bright beads of light during the May 15, 1836 annular solar eclipse. And, even though Sir Francis was not the first person to observe this phenomenon, he was the first to publish his observations.
        \n\nThis image was taken by Talha Zia in Sukkur, Pakistan. Talha did not use a solar filter, which can be dangerous. To protect their eyes, Talha did not look into the lens. Talha set up a camera with a telescope on a motorized mount that followed the Sun. To protect the camera lens, Talha limited the amount of light by setting a very short exposure time.
        \n\nVisit the Rumble Map to explore this image of Baily\’s Beads through touch and sound. The absence of light is silent and still. Can you feel and hear where the Sun\’s light creates several beads dotted along a ring of light?</string>

    <string name="annularity_description">This image is of Annularity, when an annular eclipse is at its maximum point. During Annularity, the dark black Moon appears smooth like glass and blocks the center of the Sun. Only a thin ring of light shines around the edge of the round Moon. As a result, the Sun appears to be a very bright ring of fire rather than a glowing ball.
        This ring of light may only appear for a few minutes. This spectacular feature is why annular solar eclipses are often called “Ring of Fire” eclipses. This ring shape is also why this type of eclipse is called an “annular” eclipse. This ring shape is known as an annulus in mathematics.
        The word “annular” means “little ring” in Latin. During an annular eclipse the Moon blocks all but this outer ring of the Sun\’s surface. An annular eclipse is just one type of eclipse. Total solar eclipses are another type. During a total solar eclipse the Moon completely covers the surface of the Sun.
        \n\nThis image was taken by amateur astronomer Talha Zia during the June 21, 2020 eclipse in Sukkur, Pakistan. Talha is a member of the Karachi Astronomers\’ Society. If you\'d like to photograph an eclipse, you will need more than just a telescope or camera! To protect your telescope, AND YOUR EYES, you need to use a special solar filter.
        This is similar to a very dark piece of glass that fits over the front of your camera or telescope lens. The filter is designed to limit the amount of light without adding color to the image.
        \n\nVisit the Rumble Map to explore this Annularity image through touch and sound. The absence of light is silent and still. Can you feel and hear the strong change as you move from the intensely bright “Ring of Fire” to the darkness of the Moon?</string>

    <string name="annular_phase_end_description">This image was taken as the annular phase ends. The Moon is slowly creeping away from the center of the Sun.  As the dark, circular Moon blocks less of the Sun\’s bright light, the Sun\’s fiery ring of light slowly transforms into a bright crescent shape once again. Depending on your location, Baily\’s Beads might be visible again.
        Baily’s Beads appear like glowing pearls at the ends of the Sun\’s glowing crescent.
        \n\nThis image was taken by Talha Zia in Sukkur, Pakistan. Talha did not use a solar filter on their camera, which can be dangerous. To protect their eyes, Talha did not look directly into the camera. Talha set up the camera with a telescope on a motorized mount that followed the Sun. To protect the camera, Talha limited the amount of light by setting a very short exposure time.
        \n\nVisit the Rumble Map to explore this Third Contact image through touch and sound. The absence of light is silent and still. Can you feel and hear where the widest part of the crescent shape of light is?</string>

    <string name="annular_end_description">This image is of the end of the annular eclipse. The Moon is slowly moving completely out of the Sun\’s way.
        \n\nWhile the Moon still appears as a black disk, the Sun is a fiery ball of swirling red and orange. As it moves, the Moon looks like it is taking smaller and smaller bites out of the Sun. In this image, the Moon blocks a small area on the right side of the Sun.
        \n\nFourth Contact is the end point of the annular eclipse, when the Moon\’s edge moves past the Sun\’s edge, and no longer blocks any part of the Sun\’s light.
        \n\nThis image was taken by the Atmospheric Imaging Assembly telescope on board NASA’s Solar Dynamics Observatory. This observatory is currently in orbit around the Earth. Its telescope takes eight images like this one every ten seconds. These images help scientists better understand the Sun.
        \n\nVisit the Rumble Map to explore this image of the eclipse ending through touch and sound. The absence of light is silent and still. Can you feel and hear how much more of the Sun is visible in comparison to other stages of the annular eclipse?</string>

    <string name="viewing_desc_format">Now viewing description for %1$s</string>
    <string name="viewing_image_format">Now viewing image for %1$s</string>

    <!-- Media player -->
    <string name="media_player">Media Player</string>
    <string name="audio_descriptions">Audio Descriptions</string>
    <string name="upcoming_audio">More audio descriptions coming soon…</string>

    <string name="audio_corona_full">During the totality, the moon completely covers the sun\'s glowing orb, and the sun\’s outer atmosphere is revealed.
        As if the moon were the center of a celestial sunflower, the corona appears as soft white petals, massive flumes of faint light that taper out across the sky.
        Closer to the surface of the moon\’s flat ebony circle, the corona is a swirling chaos of loops and flares. Intense fiery lines of light appear to ignite the moon\’s black edge.
        \n\nOn the Rumble Map, explore the features between the moon and the sun\’s corona.You will hear and feel variations as your fingers pass over different features of the corona.
        \n\nThe corona is the thin outer atmosphere of the Sun. With temperatures at over 1 million degrees Fahrenheit, it radiates light in wavelengths that are too short for the human eye to see (like X-rays) and that are absorbed by the Earth\’s atmosphere.
        However, the corona reflects some of the white light from the Sun\’s photosphere below it. This faint reflection is only seen when the much brighter photosphere is blocked, like during a total eclipse.</string>

    <string name="audio_helmet_streamers_full">Projections of light from the sun\'s outer atmosphere called helmet streamers extend in all directions from behind the moon.
        In contrast to the black, featureless moon, the pale, wispy streamers appear as delicate as lace. The largest streamers have a tapered shape that resemble flower petals. 
        They extend from opposite sides of the sun, with smaller rays of light between them.
        \n\nAs you trace your finger along a helmet streamer, you can feel the smooth arches come to long sharp points as they extend from the base of the Sun outward.
        \n\nHelmet streamers get their shape from two different processes. A streamer\'s arch shape is the result of magnetic fields from the Sun reaching out into the corona and then arching back down to the surface of the sun to connect to regions of opposite magnetic polarity.  
        The long, pointed tops of helmet streamers come from streams of gas flowing out from the corona into interplanetary space forming the solar wind.</string>
    
    <string name="audio_prominence_full">Fiery loops of hot pink light appear to leap off the moon\’s black surface. With the sheer white corona as their backdrop, these pink prominences seem to dance above the moon like lines of liquid neon.
        \n\nYou will notice a sharp contrast when you interact with a prominence due to its intense brightness relative to both the moon and the sun\’s corona.
        \n\nProminences are magnetic fields that are filled with very dense material making them much brighter than the surrounding background.
        The magnetic fields of prominences can be very complicated giving them complex and dynamic shapes.</string>

    <string name="audio_bailys_beads_full">On the right side of the moon, orbs of glowing sunlight shimmer off the edge of the moon\’s black disk.
        Called Baily\’s Beads, these final areas of the sun\’s light appear as glimmering pearls on a wire, made intensely bright by the absence of light surrounding them.
        \n\nOn the Rumble Map, explore the features between the moon, the sun\’s corona and Baily\’s beads which are intense and irregular.
        \n\nEven this small section of the Sun’s light cannot be viewed without special eye protection.
        Please use special eclipse glasses or filters if viewing this feature directly on the Sun with your eyes.
        Baily\’s beads appear because the moon\’s surface is not a smooth, perfect sphere.
        This spectacular feature is caused by rays of sunlight beaming through the ravines and valleys between the mountains on the moon.</string>

    <string name="audio_diamond_ring_full">On the left side of the black moon, a sliver of sunlight blasts into view with white-hot intensity. 
        As the area of re-emerging sunlight grows, it resembles a diamond, beaming out its brilliant light from its setting on the circular ring of the moon\’s edge.
        \n\nEven this small section of the sun\’s light cannot be viewed without special eye protection. Please use special eclipse glasses or filters if viewing this feature directly on the Sun with your eyes. 
        As the moon barely moves away from the solar surface, the powerful light of the Sun peers around the side of the moon. The sun\’s light is so intense that even this small fraction of it dominates the sky.</string>
    
    <string name="audio_first_contact_full">This is the first moment that the moon, slowly moving from left to right, appears to touch the sun.
        The intensity of the sun\'s light makes it unsafe to look at without special eye protection until the totality, the few minutes during which the moon completely eclipses the sun.
        The two celestial bodies appear to be the same size, although the sun\'s light is so bright that it obliterates all of the moon\'s features causing the moon to appear as a smooth, obsidian disk.
        For the next several minutes, the moon\'s black disk will creep across the sun, progressively blocking more of sun\'s light and heat until the totality.
        \n\nYou can use this time to explore Rumble Map images and audio descriptions of phenomena unique to a total eclipse.
        In the moments before, during and after totality, this app will provide a play-by-play of the action, providing images and descriptions of this rare and fascinating stellar event.
        \n\nThe outer atmosphere of the Sun, called the corona, is usually not visible from the surface of the Earth.
        To study the corona, scientists send satellites into space to make observations of the corona in wavelengths of light that the human eye cannot see, such as this image of the Sun in X-rays taken by the X-ray Telescope on the Hinode spacecraft.
        This X-ray image shows the view of the Sun being eclipsed by the moon a seen from space. A total solar eclipse provides a rare opportunity to see the corona from Earth in visible light.</string>

    <string name="audio_totality_full">This is the full eclipse, when the moon’s black disk completely covers the sun. Now, in the absence of the sun\’s full light, its massive outer corona is revealed.
        Uniquely visible during a full eclipse, grand flourishes of light called helmet streamers extend in all directions behind the moon\’s black disk.
        At the edge of the moon, the helmet streamers are intensely bright, fading to wisps of ghostly white as they stretch across space, far from the moon, like flower petals.
        \n\nOn the Rumble Map, explore the difference between the moon and the sun\’s corona.
        \n\nYou may notice changes in temperature and natural sounds, such birds and wind during the total eclipse.
        \n\nDuring the total eclipse, and only during totality, you can view the corona of the Sun without eye protection.
        The Sun\’s outer atmosphere, the corona, is in full display and viewable from the ground. The highly structured nature of the corona is clearly evident.
        This structure is caused by the Sun\’s intense and complicated magnetic field interacting with the material that makes up the corona.
        This material is called plasma, which is like a gas, but is susceptible to magnetic fields.
        The magnetic field shapes the plasma in the corona into the complicated patterns that are viewable during the eclipse.</string>

    <string name="audio_sun_as_star_full">Framed by a larger view of space, the solar wind draws helmet streamers far out into space as other stars come into view.
        Many of these stars also have planets orbiting them. Those planets can eclipse their parent star just as the moon eclipsed our sun.
        Scientists can detect planets eclipsing their stars and determine both how far the planet is from its star and the planet\’s mass.
        From these clues and other observations, scientists are attempting to discover if there is life on those other planets that may be experiencing their own eclipses.</string>

    <string name="audio_bailys_beads_short">For the next six minutes the Rumble Map will be disabled so that you can hear in real time the events surrounding totality.
        \n\nOn the right side of the moon orbs of glowing sunlight shimmer off the edge of the moon\’s black disc.
        Called Bailey\’s beads, these final areas of the sun\’s light appear as glimmering pearls on a wire made intensely bright by the absence of light surrounding them.</string>

    <string name="audio_first_contact_short">The eclipse has begun and this is the first moment that the moon appears to touch the sun.
        These two celestial bodies look as if they are the same size. The sun\’s light is so bright that it obliterates all of the moon\’s features causing the moon to appear as a smooth obsidian disc.
        For the next approximately 90 minutes you will have the opportunity to interact with the Rumble Map and explore features of the sun that are revealed during an eclipse.
        Then, during the six minutes leading up to, during, and just after totality, the Rumble Map will be disabled so that you can hear about events surrounding totality in real time.</string>

    <string name="audio_diamond_ring_short">On the left side of the black moon a sliver of sunlight blasts into view with white hot intensity.
        As the area of reemerging sunlight grows, it resembles a diamond ring beaming out its brilliant light.</string>

    <string name="audio_totality_short">THIS is the full eclipse. For approximately two minutes the moon\’s black disc completely covers the sun revealing the sun\’s massive outer corona.
        Grand flourishes of light extend from the moon in all directions like flower petals.
        Intensely bright at the moon\’s edge, these helmet streamers fade to wisps of ghostly white as they stretch across space.</string>

    <string name="audio_annular_start_short">The eclipse has begun and it is an amazing show! The Rumble Map will be disabled during the eclipse so you can enjoy this event with real time descriptions.
        And remember, you MUST wear special eye protection at ALL times if you want to look up at the annular eclipse! NEVER look at the Sun with your eyes, through binoculars or a telescope!
        \n\nDuring an annular eclipse, the Moon blocks the Sun, but not completely. From Earth, the Moon does not appear big enough to block out the Sun entirely.
        \n\nThe eclipse begins with “First Contact”. At First Contact, the Moon appears to touch the Sun. The Sun appears as a glowing, white disk against a black background.
        Near the side of the Sun, a small curved area appears missing from the Sun\’s perfect circle shape. This missing area is the Moon as it begins to creep in front of the Sun, slowly starting to block out some of the Sun\’s light.
        It appears like the Moon is taking a small “bite” out of the Sun.
        \n\nUsually the Moon\’s deep craters make the Moon appear rough. But now, the Sun\’s light is so bright that it makes all of the Moon\’s features disappear. This causes the Moon to appear black and smooth like glass.</string>

    <string name="audio_annular_phase_start_short">In this stage, the Moon has moved in front of the Sun. The Moon appears to be a completely black disk and the Sun\’s light shines only at the edges of the Moon in a thin C-shape or crescent.
        \n\nIt\’s possible that a phenomenon called Baily\’s Beads might also briefly blink into view. Baily\’s Beads look like a few glowing pearls found at the ends of the Sun\’s crescent shape. Baily\’s Beads are caused by Sunlight shining through deep valleys on the Moon.
        After Baily\’s Beads disappear, a ring of light will start to appear. The moment this phase starts is called “Second Contact.”
        \n\nIt may be tempting, but you should never look at Baily\’s Beads or the ring of light with your eyes or a telescope. You MUST wear special eye protection during all stages of an annular eclipse!</string>

    <string name="audio_annularity_short">Annularity is now happening.
        \n\nAt this point, the Sun appears to be a very bright ring of fire rather than its usual glowing ball of light. This is because the dark black Moon has moved to block the center of the Sun and the Sun\’s light glows around the circular edge of the Moon.
        As a result, the Sun\’s light resembles a glowing letter O.  This “O” shape is known as an annulus in mathematics.
        The word “annular” means “little ring” in Latin. This is why this type of eclipse is called an “annular” eclipse. During an annular eclipse the Moon obscures all but this outer ring of the Sun.
        \n\nThis ring will only appear for a few minutes because the Sun, Moon, and earth are still slowly moving.
        \n\nRemember, NEVER look directly at the Sun during an annular eclipse with a telecope or your eyes. You need to wear special eclipse glasses if you want to look at an eclipse. Otherwise, severe eye damage can occur.</string>

    <string name="audio_annular_phase_end_short">The Annular Phase is ending.
        \n\nThe Moon is slowly creeping away from the center of the Sun. As the dark, circular Moon blocks less of the Sun\’s bright light, the Sun\’s fiery ring of light slowly transforms back into a  C-shape.
        Depending on your location, Baily\’s Beads might be visible again. Baily\’s Beads appear like glowing pearls at the ends of the Sun\’s glowing crescent.
        \n\nIt is still not safe to look at the Sun with your eyes or a telescope. You MUST wear special eye protection, like official eclipse glasses, to look at the Sun during ALL stages of an annular eclipse.</string>

    <string name="audio_annular_end_short">The annular eclipse is ending. The Moon is slowly moving completely out of the Sun\’s way.
        \n\nWhile the Moon still appears as a black disk, the Sun is a fiery ball of swirling red and orange. As the Moon moves, it looks like it is taking smaller and smaller bites out of the Sun.
        \n\nAt this point, only a small section of the Sun is blocked by the Moon. Soon the Moon will no longer be blocking any of the Sun\’s light.
        \n\nFourth Contact is the end point of the annular eclipse, when the Moon\’s edge moves past the Sun\’s edge, and no longer blocks any part of the Sun\’s light.
        \n\nOnce the annular eclipse ends, the Rumble Map and all other app features will be available again. We hope you will continue to explore the wonders of eclipses using the app even after this annular eclipse\’s completion!</string>

    <string name="first_contact">First Contact</string>
    <string name="bailys_beads">Baily\'s Beads</string>
    <string name="bailys_beads_closeup">Baily\'s Beads Closeup</string>
    <string name="corona">Corona</string>
    <string name="diamond_ring">Diamond Ring</string>
    <string name="helmet_streamers">Helmet Streamers</string>
    <string name="helmet_streamers_closeup">Helmet Streamers Closeup</string>
    <string name="prominence">Prominence</string>
    <string name="prominence_closeup">Prominence Closeup</string>
    <string name="totality">Totality</string>
    <string name="annular_start">The Annular Eclipse Begins</string>
    <string name="annular_phase_start">Annular Phase Begins</string>
    <string name="annularity">Annularity</string>
    <string name="annular_phase_end">Annular Phase Ends</string>
    <string name="annular_end">The Annular Eclipse Ends</string>
    <string name="sun_as_star">Sun as a Star</string>
    <string name="eclipse_experience">Eclipse Experience</string>
    <string name="duration_desc_seconds">%1$s seconds</string>
    <string name="duration_desc_minute">One minute, %1$s seconds</string>
    <string name="duration_desc_minutes">%1$s minutes, %2$s seconds</string>
    <string name="duration_current_progress">%1$s of %2$s</string>
    <string name="duration_min_sec">%1$s minutes and %2$s seconds</string>

    <string name="total_solar_eclipse">Total Solar Eclipse</string>
    <string name="annular_solar_eclipse">Annular Solar Eclipse</string>

    <!-- rumble map interaction -->
    <string name="rumble_map">Rumble Map</string>
    <string name="rumble_maps">Rumble Maps</string>
    <string name="rumble_map_interaction">Rumble Map Interaction</string>
    <string name="rumble_map_launch">Press to interact with Rumble Map</string>
    <string name="rumble_map_how">How to Use The Rumble Map</string>
    <string name="rumble_map_instructions_title">Rumble Map Instructions</string>
    <string name="rumble_map_instructions">To use the Rumble Map, touch your screen with only one finger. The map will produce audio tones and vibrations depending on how much light is underneath that particular spot. For best results, drag your finger across the touchscreen slowly. As you move your finger onto the bright sections of the Sun, your phone will vibrate more and produce a sharper, more pronounced audio tone. As you move your finger into the dark spaces blocked by the Moon’s disk, the vibration will diminish as the audio tone darkens and disappears. At times, you may hear a metronome-like ticking sound: that means you have entered an area of total darkness, either on the face of the Moon, or in the dark space outside the sphere of the Sun. By paying close attention to the audio tones and the strength of your phone’s vibration, you can learn how much sunlight is visible at each stage of the eclipse, and even explore some of the fascinating features of the Sun’s corona such as Baily’s Beads, Helmet Streamers, Prominences, and the Diamond Ring effect. If a specific section of an image interests you and you want to return to it later, hold down your finger in one place until you hear a “blip” noise. You’ve created a marker! Next time your finger passes over this point, you will hear the “blip” again so you can continue to explore that area.</string>
    <string name="rumble_map_inactive">Rumble Map Inactive, Double Tap to turn on</string>
    <string name="rumble_map_running">Rumble Map Running, Double Tap to turn off</string>

    <!-- About -->
    <string name="supported_eclipse">Eclipses We Support</string>
    <string name="link_feedback_form" translatable="false"><![CDATA[https://eclipsesoundscapes.org/ES_MobileApp_Feedback]]></string>
    <string name="privacy_policy_url" translatable="false"><![CDATA[https://eclipsesoundscapes.org/privacy-policy]]></string>
    <string name="tos_url" translatable="false"><![CDATA[https://eclipsesoundscapes.org/Terms-of-Service]]></string>

    <!-- Walkthrough -->
    <string name="walkthrough">Walkthrough</string>
    <string name="walkthrough_title">Eclipse Soundscapes Walkthrough</string>
    <string name="walkthrough_title_location">Please allow location access</string>
    <string name="walkthrough_location_page">Access to location</string>
    <string name="not_now">Not Now</string>
    <string name="walkthrough_welcome_text">Thank you for downloading the Eclipse Soundscapes app, a multi-sensory experience for people of all learning styles to engage with astronomical events, including annular and total solar eclipses.
        Inside this app, you will find countdowns to major astronomical events in your area, and real time narrations of those events with illustrative audio descriptions. You can also explore the cosmos with high quality photos, educational information, and accessible learning tools.
        This app is available in English and Spanish. To change the language within the application, go to the Menu.</string>
    <string name="walkthrough_rumble_map_text">Our Rumble Map tool is designed for you to hear and feel astronomical phenomena, such as eclipses, using the touchscreen and the speakers on your smartphone. For example: the Rumble Map will display photos of the Moon passing in front of the Sun during the most engaging and educational moments of an eclipse. When you touch the image on the screen, the app will read the grayscale value of a pixel underneath your finger, and play an audio tone which will vibrate your phone with a strength relative to the brightness of that section. As you move your finger onto the bright sections of the Sun, your phone will vibrate more. As you move your finger into the dark spaces blocked by the Moon’s disk, the vibration will diminish and disappear. By paying close attention to the audio tones and the strength of your phone\'s vibration, you can learn how much sunlight is visible at each stage of the eclipse, and explore some of the fascinating features of the Sun\'s corona.</string>
    <string name="walkthrough_eclipse_center">The Eclipse Center is your go-to destination for learning about eclipses in your area so you can discover them as they happen. When you open the Eclipse Center, it will ask to pinpoint your geographic location. Once you accept, you will find a countdown to the next eclipse, information on whether you will experience a total or a partial solar eclipse in your area, and the exact start time, peak time, and end time of the eclipse. </string>
    <string name="walkthrough_audio_description">When it is time for the next eclipse to start, you will receive a push notification to open Eclipse Soundscapes. The app will then guide you through the main event with illustrative audio descriptions of an eclipse\'s most important moments. These audio descriptions, provided by the National Center for Accessible Media, are explanations of photos developed with specialized language to help people who are blind and visually impaired engage with an eclipse. After each audio description ends, you will have the option to either hear more educational information or explore that feature of an eclipse using the Rumble Map.</string>
    <string name="walkthrough_permission">You don\'t want to miss this amazing astronomical event! We\'ll need access to your location to show you information about the eclipse.</string>

    <string name="prev_page">previous page</string>
    <string name="next_page">next page</string>
    <string name="page_indicator">Page %1$d of %2$d</string>

    <!-- Future Eclipses -->
    <string name="future_eclipse_label_format">%1$s: %2$s</string>
    <string name="future_eclipse_features">Tracking, Rumble Maps, Narrations</string>

    <!-- Photo credits -->
    <string name="credits_diamond_ring">©1991 Bill Reyna\n©2005 Hana Druckmüllerová, Miloslav Druckmüller</string>
    <string name="credits_helmet_streamers">©1994 Úpice Observatory and Vojtech Rušin\n©2007 Miloslav Druckmüller</string>
    <string name="credits_prominence">©1991 Peter Aniol\n©2010 Miloslav Druckmüller</string>
    <string name="credits_sun_as_star">©2006 Martin Antoš, Hana Druckmüllerová, Miloslav Druckmüller, ESA/NASA</string>
    <string name="credits_first_contact">XRT team(SAO, NASA, JAXA, NAOJ)</string>
    <string name="credits_totality">©2006 Miloslav Druckmüller, Peter Aniol</string>
    <string name="credits_bailys_beads">©2013 Úpice observatory Petr Horálek, Jan Sládeček\n©2014 Miloslav Duckmüller </string>
    <string name="credits_corona">©2002 Arne Danielsen\n©2005 Miloslav Druckmüller</string>
    <string name="credits_annular_start">© Rick Fienberg</string>
    <string name="credits_annular_phase_start">© Ajay Talwar</string>
    <string name="credits_annularity">© 2020 Talha Zia</string>
    <string name="credits_annular_phase_end">© Ajay Talwar</string>
    <string name="credits_annular_end">Courtesy of NASA/SDO and the AIA, EVE, and HMI science teams</string>
    <string name="credits_link_diamond_ring">http://www.zam.fme.vutbr.cz/~druck/eclipse/Ecl1991m/Ecl1991_rdd_dr/0-info.htm</string>
    <string name="credits_link_helmet_streamers">http://www.zam.fme.vutbr.cz/~druck/eclipse/Ecl1994ch/Mid_ecl/0-info.htm</string>
    <string name="credits_link_prominence">http://www.zam.fme.vutbr.cz/~druck/eclipse/Ecl1991a/Ecl1991a_in03/0-info.htm</string>
    <string name="credits_link_sun_as_star">http://www.zam.fme.vutbr.cz/~druck/eclipse/Ecl2006th/Tse2006tc_m200_inh30_32_c3/0-info.htm</string>
    <string name="credits_link_first_contact">https://xrt.cfa.harvard.edu/xpow/20160315.html</string>
    <string name="credits_link_totality">http://www.zam.fme.vutbr.cz/~druck/eclipse/ecl2006l/Tse2006l_1640_15/0-info.htm</string>
    <string name="credits_link_bailys_beads">http://www.zam.fme.vutbr.cz/~druck/eclipse/Ecl2013u/Tse_2013_bp-7430/0-info.htm</string>
    <string name="credits_link_corona">http://www.zam.fme.vutbr.cz/~druck/eclipse/Ecl2002a/Ecl2002_dd_cor/0-info.htm</string>
    <string name="credits_link_annular_start">https://eclipse.aas.org/resources/images-videos#partial</string>
    <string name="credits_link_annular_phase_start">http://xjubier.free.fr/en/site_pages/solar_eclipses/ASE_20200621_pg02.html</string>
    <string name="credits_link_annularity">http://xjubier.free.fr/en/site_pages/solar_eclipses/ASE_19840530_pg01.html</string>
    <string name="credits_link_annular_phase_end">http://xjubier.free.fr/en/site_pages/solar_eclipses/ASE_20200621_pg02.html</string>
    <string name="credits_link_annular_end">https://sdo.gsfc.nasa.gov/gallery/main/item/131</string>

    <string name="our_partners">Our Partners</string>
    <string name="current_partners">Current Partners</string>
    <string name="past_partners">Past Partners</string>
    <string name="our_team">Our Team</string>
    <string name="feedback">Give Feedback</string>

    <array name="current_partners_title">
        <item name="partner_nasa">NASA Heliophysics Educational Activation Team (HEAT)</item>
        <item name="partner_wgbh">National Center for Accessible Media, GBH</item>
        <item name="partner_nfb">National Federation of the Blind</item>
        <item name="partner_science_friday">Science Friday</item>
    </array>

    <array name="past_partners_title">
        <item name="partner_national_park">National Park Service</item>
        <item name="partner_eclipse_mob">Eclipse Mob</item>
        <item name="partner_smithsonian">Smithsonian Institution</item>
        <item name="partner_national_girls_collab">National Girls Collaborative</item>
        <item name="partner_citizen_cate">Citizen CATE</item>
        <item name="partner_bridham_uni">Brigham Young University, Idaho</item>
    </array>

    <array name="current_partners_desc">
        <item name="nasa_description">NASA (National Aeronautics and Space Administration) is an independent agency of the United States federal government which conducts the civilian space program, aeronautics, and aerospace research.
            NASA is leading an educational outreach effort surrounding eclipses, which includes information and live coverage of these events.
            For more information on NASA, visit nasa.gov. The NASA Space Science Education Consortium (NSSEC) capitalizes on NASA\’s rich history of sharing research and technology through compelling and innovative education projects.
            The NSSEC (formerly the Heliophysics Education Consortium (HEC)) continues the Science Mission Directorate\’s (SMD) work at the forefront of NASA\’s educational endeavors by linking exciting science and missions directly to the American public.
            NSSEC is partnering with Eclipse Soundscapes to provide the script calculating the timing of the eclipse, as well as the funding that makes Eclipse Soundscapes possible.
        </item>

        <item name="wgbh_description">The Carl and Ruth Shapiro Family National Center for Accessible Media (NCAM) is a non-profit branch of GBH in Boston which is dedicated to achieving media access equality for people with disabilities.
            NCAM is partnering with Eclipse Soundscapes to provide media coverage of the eclipse, including illustrative audio descriptions of the eclipse which will allow visually impaired individuals to experience the eclipse through real-time audio narrations.
            NCAM is also conducting a review of the Eclipse Soundscapes app to enhance its accessibility.
        </item>

        <item name="nfb_description">The National Federation of the Blind is the oldest and largest nationwide organization of blind Americans.
            Founded in 1940 and currently headquartered in Baltimore, the NFB consists of affiliates, chapters, and divisions in all fifty states, Washington, DC, and Puerto Rico.
        </item>

        <item name="science_friday_description">The Science Friday Initiative is a non-profit organization dedicated to increasing the public\’s access to science and scientific information.
            They host a radio show distributed by Public Radio International (PRI) and produce science and technology related digital videos, original web articles, and educational resources for educators.
            Science Friday is partnering with Eclipse Soundscapes to provide audio recordings and social media support for the project.
        </item>
    </array>

    <array name="past_partners_desc">
        <item name="national_park_description">The National Park Service (NPS), an agency of the United States Department of the Interior, manages national parks, monuments, conservation, and historical sites throughout the United States.
            NPS is partnering with Eclipse Soundscapes during the August 2017 Eclipse to collect mono and binaural field recordings in parks across the country, especially those in the path of totality.
            They will collect data the day before, the day of, and the day after the eclipse in order to study how wildlife sounds fluctuate with the changes in light and temperature caused by the eclipse.
        </item>

        <item name="eclipse_mob_description">Eclipse Mob is a crowdsourced effort to conduct the largest-ever low-frequency radio wave propagation experiment during the 2017 solar eclipse.
            They are using radio signals to study the effect of sunlight on the ionosphere. By crowdsourcing, Eclipse Mob can collect radio wave signals at locations across the United States, allowing them to study how the signals are affected as they travel along various paths.
            Eclipse Mob is partnering with Eclipse Soundscapes to provide radio wave data (a form of audio data) the Eclipse Soundscapes database.
        </item>

        <item name="smithsonian_description">The Smithsonian Institution is a group of museums and research centers established and administered by the United States government.
            Among the Smithsonian\’s many facilities are the National Air and Space Museum and the Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics, where Eclipse Soundscapes is based.
            The Smithsonian is partnering with Eclipse Soundscapes to provide a headquarters and funding for the Eclipse Soundscapes project.
        </item>

        <item name="nation_girls_collab_description">The National Girls Collaborative Project (NGC) brings together United States organizations that are committed to informing and encouraging girls to pursue careers in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.
            NGC is partnering with Eclipse Soundscapes to organize listening parties where young women can experience the total solar eclipse complete with audio information.
        </item>

        <item name="citizen_cate">The Citizen CATE (Continental-America Telescopic Eclipse) Experiment is an effort to document the 2017 Eclipse by capturing images of the inner solar corona using a network of more than 60 telescopes.
            CATE is working with high schools, universities, education groups, astronomy clubs, national science research labs, and corporate sponsors to produce 90 minutes of continuous, high-resolution, and rapid-cadence images detailing the Sun\’s inner corona.
            Citizen CATE is partnering with Eclipse Soundscapes to provide high quality images for the Eclipse Soundscapes app.
        </item>

        <item name="brigham_young_uni_description">Brigham Young University (BYU) is a private research university with three locations, including Rexburg, Idaho.
            They are partnering with Eclipse Soundscapes to provide a series of field recordings of the 2017 Eclipse, including audio of an active beehive.
            Because Rexburg lies in the path of totality, BYU is hosting a number of viewing and educational events with the City of Rexburg.
        </item>
    </array>

    <array name="current_partners_link">
        <item name="nasa_link">https://www.nasa.gov/</item>
        <item name="gbh_link">http://ncam.wgbh.org/</item>
        <item name="nfb_link">http://nfb.org/</item>
        <item name="science_friday_link">https://sciencefriday.com/</item>
    </array>

    <array name="past_partners_link">
        <item name="national_park_link">nps.gov/</item>
        <item name="eclipse_mob_link">eclipsemob.org</item>
        <item name="smithsonian_link">si.edu</item>
        <item name="national_girls_collab_link">ngcproject.org/</item>
        <item name="citizen_cate">eclipse2017.nso.edu/citizen-cate/</item>
        <item name="brigham_uni_link">byui.edu/eclipse-2017</item>
    </array>

    <array name="team">
        <item name="member_henry_winter">Dr. Henry Winter</item>
        <item name="member_marykay">MaryKay Severino</item>
        <item name="member_arlindo">Arlindo Goncalves</item>
        <item name="member_joel">Joel Goncalves</item>
        <item name="member_miles">Miles Gordon</item>
        <item name="member_kristin">Kristin DiVona</item>
        <item name="member_kelsey">Kelsey Perrett</item>
    </array>

    <array name="team_title">
        <item name="member_henry_winter">Co-Principal Investigator</item>
        <item name="member_marykay">Co-Principal Investigator</item>
        <item name="member_arlindo">Application Developer</item>
        <item name="member_joel">Application Developer</item>
        <item name="member_miles">Audio Engineer</item>
        <item name="member_kristin">Graphic Designer</item>
        <item name="member_kelsey">Social Media Coordinator/Content Writer</item>
    </array>

    <array name="team_bio">
        <item name="member_henry_winter">Dr. Henry \"Trae\" Winter III, is the Chief Scientist and Co-Founder of the ARISA Lab.
            Dr. Winter has worked on eight NASA missions observing the Sun. His primary research focus is improving computer simulations to explore energy is released in the Sun\'s atmosphere, the corona, and in other stars.
            Dr. Winter has designed video wall exhibits for the Cooper-Hewitt National Design Museum, the National Air and Space Museum, North Carolina State University\’s Hunt Library, and the Harvard Art Museums\’ Lightbox Gallery.
            In addition to Eclipse Soundscapes, his current project \“The Tactile Sun\” aims to engage the blind and visually disabled community with universally designed solar exhibits.
        </item>

        <item name="member_marykay">MaryKay Severino is the Educational Director and Co-Founder of the ARISA Lab.
            After earning a business degree from Villanova University, she worked in South Carolina and California as a Program Manager and Marketing Consultant.
            Realizing she was ready for a change, she went on to earn her Master\'s degree in Education and worked in public school systems and universities in Italy, Taiwan, and South Korea.
            Living abroad, immersed in other cultures and navigating daily life with language and literacy barriers, gave MaryKay a strong understanding of the challenges faced by anyone who communicates differently.
            For this reason, the Eclipse Soundscapes project was a natural fit. She is excited to use her skills to promote, plan, and execute a project which will bring the amazement and wonder of an eclipse to a more inclusive demographic.
        </item>

        <item name="member_arlindo">
            Arlindo Goncalves is an iOS developer from Brockton, Massachusetts.
            He aspires to develop applications that help schools and other institutions engage youth, making education a focal point in their lives.
            In his free time, Arlindo enjoys playing soccer and cooking for his family and friends.
        </item>

        <item name="member_joel">Joel Goncalves is a software engineer from Brockton, Massachusetts and a Computer Science graduate from the University of Massachusetts, Boston.
            As an engineer, he is passionate about creating and contributing to meaningful applications.
            As a hobby, he likes to hike, travel and play sports.
        </item>

        <item name="member_miles">Miles Gordon is an audio engineer and multimedia artist from New England.
            Between mixing and mastering tracks for his friends and his work on the Eclipse Soundscapes project, he also enjoys tinkering with machines and editing papers for a Chinese translation company.
            When he grows up, he wants to be a supporting character in a William Gibson novel. Miles got involved in the Eclipse Soundscapes Project after a mutual friend introduced him to Dr. Winter.
            Their shared enthusiasm for innovation in audio engineering led to a collaboration on Eclipse Soundscapes.
        </item>

        <item name="member_kristin">Kristin DiVona is the Visual Information Specialist for NASA\'s Chandra X-Ray Observatory.
            An award-winning designer and illustrator, she is responsible for the creation of printed materials, exhibits, and interactive educational tools that visually interpret concepts related to astrophysics and x-ray astronomy— connecting everyday life to science exploration and technology.
            (Yes, it\'s as cool as it sounds.) She is a graduate of Rhode Island School of Design. Kristin is waiting not-so-patiently for this amazing astronomical event, and is excited to work with the Eclipse Soundscapes team on this inclusive design project.
        </item>

        <item name="member_kelsey">Kelsey Perrett is a Massachusetts-based freelance writer, editor, web producer, and social media specialist.
            She enjoys writing about travel, health and fitness, and the environment. When she isn\’t writing, she can be found outside exploring trails, at the gym/yoga studio, or attempting to conquer an ever-expanding reading list.
            Kelsey got involved in the Eclipse Soundscapes Project due to her interest in environmental reporting, and is thrilled to work with a talented group to make the wonders of space accessible to everyone.
        </item>
    </array>

    <string name="libraries_use_detail">The following sets forth attribution notices for third party software that may be contained in portions of the Eclipse Soundscapes product.
        We thank the open sources community for all of their contributions.\n</string>

</resources>

